Guide to the Stanford University, Administrative Council, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Administrative Council, records
1981-1989
SC0353
Stanford University. Administrative Council.
22.5 Linear feet
Agendas, minutes, supporting documents, and background materials from Administrative Council meetings, 1981-1989; records pertaining to fundraising and Stanford Centennial activities, 1982-1988; and records from the Vice Presidents' Group meetings, 1991-92.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, 1988, 1991, and 1999.
Information about Access
Accession 1988-087 and 1991-144 Boxes 1-2 are restricted 75 years from date of creation. The rest of the materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Administrative Council was the senior internal decision-making and advisory body on administrative policy, significant institutional policy, and related matters. It ceased meeting in 1990.
Description of the Collection
Agendas, minutes, supporting documents, and background materials from Administrative Council meetings, 1981-1989; records pertaining to fundraising and Stanford Centennial activities, 1982-1988; and records from the Vice Presidents' Group meetings, 1991-92.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Administrative Council.; Stanford University. Administrative Council.; College administrators.; Universities and colleges--Administration.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1988-087
  Restricted 75 years from date of creation.
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, April 1981 - July 1981; August 1981 - December 1981; January 1982 - May 1982 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, June 1982 - December 1982; January 1983 - April 1983; May 1983 - July 1983 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, August 1983 - December 1983; January 1984 - June 1984; June 1984 - December 1984 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, January 1985 - June 1985; July 1985 - December 1985; January 1986 - March 1986 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, April 1986 - August 1986; September 1986 - December 1986 (Box 5)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1991-144
  Boxes 1-2 restricted 75 years from date of creation.
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, January - April 15, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, April 29 - August 15, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, August 19 - December 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, January - May 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, June - December 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Council Unofficial Meeting Records, January - May 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Green Folders Working File (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Green Folders Group Meetings Records, September 24, 1985 - May 17, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2-47)
  - Centennial Campaign Coordinating Committee Meeting Records, 12/7/84 - 9/24/85 (Box 3, Folder 48-65)
  - Fundraising (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Fundraising: Campaign for Stanford Building Components (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Fundraising: Forming Local Support Groups (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Fundraising: Access to Prospects (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Fundraising: Approvals and Prior Mts. with Provost, Deans (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Fundraising: Standard Responses to Fundraising requests (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Fundraising: Solicitation and Uses of Gifts (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Fundraising: Campaign for Stanford (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Fundraising: Research Policy-Sponsored Projects (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Development Priorities Committee Meeting Records, 10/8/85 - 12/5/88 (Box 4, Folder 1-49)
  - Green Folders Group Meeting Records, 6/28/88 - 12/5/88 (Box 4, Folder 45-49)
  - Centennial Chron File, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Centennial Chron File, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Centennial Chron File, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Centennial Chron File, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Centennial Chron File, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Chron File, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Centennial Chron File, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Senate Advisory Committee on Centennial Campaign Planning (SAC-CCP), responses to 2/1/85 Ryan memo (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - SAC-CCP Meeting 2/19/86 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - SAC-CCP Meetings 5/14/85 - 12/3/86 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - SAC-CCP Report to the Senate, 2/19/87 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - SAC-CCP Meeting, 12/18/85 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - SAC-CCP Minutes and Agendas (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - SAC-CCP Submissions and Ryan Responses (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Deans and the Centennial, Letters (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1999-267
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and background documents for meetings, December 1982-December 1984 (Box 1)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and background documents for meetings, January 1985 – August 6, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and background documents for meetings, August 20, 1986 – January 1988 (Box 3)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and background documents for meetings, February 1988 – September 27, 1989 and February 7, 1990 – May 30, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and background documents for meetings, October 4, 1989 – January 31, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and background documents for meetings, June 1990 – September 1990
    - Miscellaneous documents: Facilities Plan and Funding Forecast 1984-1987 (Sept. 1984); Final Report of the University Committee on Minority Issues (March 1989); Stanford University Self-Study on Building a Multiracial Multicultural University Community (April 1990) (Box 5)
  - Vice Presidents' Group Meetings records (correspondence, agenda, notes, etc. kept by Lowell Price), November 1991 – September 1992 (Box 6-7)